# **Keegan McRoberts**

Kansas City, MO | 816-215-8140 | keegan.mcroberts@gmail.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Blog

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Full Stack Web Developer with experience in JavaScript, React and Ruby on Rails and a background in Public Health. The decision to make a career transition came from a desire to combine my passion for creative design and an affinity for helping people. My strengths lie in collaboration, communication and being adaptable to change. I look forward to growing my repertoire of programming languages and web frameworks and contributing my skills towards building user-friendly web applications.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, OOP, Ruby, Sinatra, Rails, CSS, HTML, JSON, PostgreSQL, Active Record, Git

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Concert Legend - Github | Demo

A concert tracking website which allows easy access for finding upcoming shows by date, city, venue, or band.

- Constructed with ReactJS front-end and customized CSS in order to provide a seamless user experience and easy website navigation.
- Customized a database schema built with the MVC pattern in Ruby on Rails to simulate the experience of viewing real-life upcoming concerts.
- Utilized BCrypt for user authentication/authorization in order to ensure safe and secure login.

## Um - Github | Demo

A new take on everybody's favorite family-friendly card game, Uno.

- Customized a ReactJS front-end with unique CSS to simulate a true online game-like experience for the user.
- Integrated personalized card data using the MVC pattern in Rails in order to seamlessly fetch the database.
- Built fully functioning Uno logic for each unique card using JavaScript front-end to provide a full-game experience.

## Immersive Game Review - Github | Demo

An immersive game app where users can see their favorite games, game trailers, game scores, and game reviews.

- Created fully with ReactJS on the front-end and custom db.JSON framework.
- Embedded video players using third-party React components in order to view game trailers.
- Incorporated pre-built JavaScript classes such as the Audio object to add soundtrack listening.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Trumpet Behavioral Health, Overland Park, KS

08/2021 - 05/2022

Registered Behavior Technician

- Built interpersonal and social skills useful for everyday activities and interactions.
- Designed and implemented patient-specific interventions as part of behavior treatment plans.
- Instructed team members on proper implementation of applied behavior analysis programs and interventions.
- Collected and analyzed data and monitored progress and efficacy of individualized treatment plans.

#### Whole Foods Market, Kansas City, MO

11/2020 - 04/2021

Bakery Team Member

- Managed inventory, maintained an organized bakery, and oversaw closing down the bakery.
- Instructed new team members by detailing daily tasks and explaining workplace safety procedures.
- Provided excellent customer-service with a customer-first mindset

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Flatiron School, New York, NY

06/2022 - 09/2022

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO Bachelor of Science, Health and Exercise Science 08/2015 - 12/2019